A Guide to the Equal Suffrage League of Virginia records, 1908-1938
Library of Virginia
- Series VI: General and Miscellaneous Files., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 22-28)
  - Organizations., 3 boxes (Box 22-24)
    - Progressive Party broadsides, 1912 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Red Cross (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Republican National Committee--Wanted--A New Business Management for the United States (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Richmond Education Association fourth annual report, 1903-1904 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - Southern States Woman Suffrage Conference second annual convention, 11-13 December 1915 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Southern States Woman Suffrage Conference--Kate Gordon Chapter, Le Jardin de Danse, 14 February [19?] (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Southern States Woman Suffrage Conference--The Southern Problem (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - State Central Committee of Suffrage Amendment Alliance leaflet, ca. 1917 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - University of Virginia Institute of Public Affairs roundtable on unemployment, 10-15 July 1933 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - University of Virginia Institute of Public Affairs roundtable on unemployment, 10-15 July 1933 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute and United States Department of Agriculture, Extension Division--Virginia's Defense is in Safe Farming (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - Virginia Association Opposed to Woman's Suffrage pamphlets and broadsides (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - Virginia Democratic Party leaflet, 1913 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind commencement exercises, 11-12 June 1912 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - Virginia Women's Council of Legislative Chairmen of State Organizations--stationery and notes (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - Wage Earners' Suffrage League (New York) leaflets (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Woman's Christian Temperance Union of Virginia 30th annual convention, 30 September-3 October 1912 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Woman's Club of Chicago--Chicago Women as Citizens, 1910-1911 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Woman's Club of NorfolkKate Waller Barrett memorial meeting, 30 November [1925?] (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Woman's Club of Richmond fifteenth annual report, 1909 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Women's International League annual meeting, 30 April-3 May [1937] (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Woman's Peace Party--The Trojan Women, Euripides (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Woman Suffrage Party--Home and State (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - New York State Woman Suffrage Party pamphlets and broadsides (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - New York State Woman Suffrage Party sample ballot, Ulster County, November 1917 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Woman Suffrage Party of New York City papers, 1916-1917 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Woman Suffrage Party of New York City The Woman Voter, September 1916 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - YWCA papers, 1920-1921 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Government publications and papers., 2 boxes (Box 24-25)
    - Virginia Constitution, 1908 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Constitution--amendments ratified, November 1912 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Constitution--proposed amendments, 1912-1916, [1923?], undated (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Code of Virginia--presidential and vice-presidential electors; tax code, 8 March 1918 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Code of Virginia--tax bill and revenue act, 8 March 1918 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Code of Virginia--bills to amend code--rape and seduction, 1918 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - Code of Virginia bill to amend and re-enact section 54, electors for president and vice-president, undated (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Virginia--general laws amendment for chapter 17, election of electors of president and vice president, [1919] (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Virginia General Assembly--granting women the right to vote for electors for president and vice president of the United States (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Virginia General Assembly--bill extending the right of suffrage to women (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Virginia General Assembly--laws bearing on labor, 1 March 1909 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Virginia General Assembly--an act to provide for indigent widowed mothers, 28 February 1918 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Virginia General Assembly--a bill to provide for the support of illegitimate children, [1918] (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Virginia General Assembly--bill to establish a minimum wage for women and minors, [1918] (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Virginia General Assembly--bill to provide censorshiop for moving pictures, [1918] (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Virginia General Assembly--Acts of Assemlby chapter 400--women entitled to register, 1920 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Virginia General Assembly--digest of bills submitted to the General Assembly by the Children's Code Commission and other agencies, 1921 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Virginia General Assembly Senate--bills on woman suffrage, child labor (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - Virginia General Assembly House of Delegates--bills referred (including reference to suffrage), 24 February 1920 (Box 24, Folder 32)
    - Virginia General Assembly Senate-joint resolutions, proposed amendments concerning elective franchise and qualifications for office, 1912, 1914, 1916, and undated (Box 24, Folder 33)
    - Virginia General Assembly--joint resolutions rejecting suffrage amendment to the U.S. Constitution, undated (Box 24, Folder 34)
    - Virginia General Assembly--join resolutions regarding ratification of the U.S. suffrage amendment, ca. 1920 (Box 24, Folder 35)
    - Virginia General Assembly Senate--Senate joint resolution no. 2 and amendments, [192?] (Box 24, Folder 36)
    - Virginia General Assembly House of Delegates--suffrage resolutions, 1920 (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Virginia General Assembly--joint resolutions on taxation and finance and on poll tax, 1914, undated (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Virginia General Assembly Senate--joint resolutions on construction of dam at Muscle Shoals, Alabama; school districts; and extra session, 30 January 1918, 1918, 3 August 1919 (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Virginia General Assembly House of Delegates--calendar, 9 March 1914, 28 February, 3, 12 March 1920 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Virginia General Assembly Senate--calendar, 3, 27 February, 3 March 1920 (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth--primary election laws of Virginia, 1915 (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Virginia Department of Agriculture and Immigration--Farmers' bulletin no. 20 The Home Vegetable Garden, undated (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Industrial Commission of Virginia--Workmen's Compensation Law, 1920 (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Virginia Commission on Simplification and Economy of State and Local Government report, January 1924 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - Richmond--Annual Report of the Health Department, 1908 (Box 24, Folder 46)
    - Richmond--Annual Report of the Health Department, 1909 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - University of Virginia Record Extension Series--Conference on Governmental Efficiency, 22-22 November 1921 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - University of Virginia Record Extension Series--Institute of Citizenship and Government, 18-19 July 1923, 17-20 May 1927 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - University of Virginia Record Extension Series--Handbook of Electon Law for the Virginia Voter, March 1925 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - United States Congress--speeches on Woman Suffrage, 1915, 1918 Hon. John W. Abercrombie of Alabama (House of Representatives), 12 January 1915; Hon. Perl D. Decker and Hon. Scott Ferris, (House of Representatives), 10 January 1918; and Hon. Morris Sheppard (Senate), 5 August 1918 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - United States Congress--Congressional Record, 1910, 1919 list of committee members in Senate, 15 Decemeber 1910; Speech of Hon. William P. Pollock (Senate) 10 February 1919 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - United States Congress Senate--memorials, 1909, 1910 memorial of Mr. Vere Goldthwaite, 5 January 1909; memorial of the National American Woman's Suffrage Association, 3 May 1910 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - United States Senate--Committee on Woman Suffrage, 1910, 1917 statement of John Shafroth, Governor of Colorado, 1910; extracts of hearing statements by Thomas J. Walsh and Carrie Chapman Catt, 20 April 1917 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Congress House of Representatives--speech of Hon. John J. Esch of Wisconsin on the Match Bill, 27 February 1911 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Congress House of Representatives--hearing before the Committee on the Judiciary, 1910, 1915-1917 woman suffrage, 19 April 1910; woman suffrage, 16 December 1915, February 1916; views of the minority, 10 January 1917 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - United States Congress--bills and resolutions, 1920, 1924 bill for the public protection of maternity and infancy, 1920; resolution to limit, regulate, and prohibit labor of persons under 18, 28 March 1924 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - United States Civil Works Administration (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - United States Department of the Interior, Office of Education informational letters, ca. 1933-1934 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - United States Department of Labor, Children's Bureau--Recent Developments in the Child-Labor Field, January 1933 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - United States Department of Labor, Woman's Bureau--Hours and Conditions of Work for Women in Industry in Virginia, March 1920 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - United States Department of Labor, United States Employment Service--Guide to the Organization and Operation of Reemployment Offices, 22 July 1933 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - States--Connecticut State Council of Defense, Health and Recreation Bureau chart (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - States--Mississippi State Board of Public Welfare, publications, bulletins, and forms, 1932 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - States--laws referring to woman's suffrage and amendment, 1913-1919 Illinois, Indiana, Missouri, Oklahoma, and Tennessee (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - England, Australia, and International., 2 boxes (Box 25-26)
    - Parliamentary Debates: Women's Enfranchisement Bill, 5 May 1911 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Artists' Suffrage League flyer, undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Central Society for Women's Suffrage--Women's Suffrage in New Zealand and Australia (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - The Church League for Women's Suffrage--From East to West: Women's Suffrage in Relation to Foreign Missions, July 1910 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - The Fabian Women's Group--How the National Insurance Bill Affects Women (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - London Society for Women's Suffrage--Report of the Executive Committee Presented at the Annual General Meeting, 8 December 1910 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - London Society for Women's Suffrage pamphlets and leaflets, 1909, undated (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Men's League for Women's Suffrage--Open Letter to the Prime Minister, June 1910 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - National Union of Women's Suffrage Societies pamphlets and booklets (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - National Women's Social and Political Union programs, 1911, undated (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - National Women's Social and Political Union pamphlets and booklets, titles E-M (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - National Women's Social and Political Union pamphlets and booklets, titles O-W (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - [National]Women's Social and Political Union--A Women's Demonstration in the Royal Albert Hall, 23 March 1911 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - [National] Women's Social and Political Union poster--Mrs. Pankhurst Will speak at a Public Meeting, 3 June [----] (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - National Women's Social and Political Union--Woman This, and Woman That (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Women's Freedom League--pamphlets (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Women's National Anti-Suffrage League--Anti-Suffrage Review, July 1910 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Women Writers' Suffrage League--Why? 1910 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous pamphlets--A Brief Review of the Women's Suffrage Movement Since Its Beginning and Mary Wollstonecraft and the Women's Movement of Today (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous flyer and poster--Testimony of the Australian Parliament on Equal Suffrage and Votes for Women Householders, February 1910, 1911 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - International Woman Suffrage Alliance--Report of the Seventh Congress, 15-21 June 1913 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - International Woman Suffrage Alliance--Jus Suffragii, pp. 57-60, 1 January 1914 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - International Woman Suffrage Alliance/New Zealand Council of Women--Woman Suffrage in New Zealand, ca. 1907 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - General Publications., 2 boxes (Box 26-27)
    - Woman Citizen (cover only), 10 May 1919 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Woman Citizen, 23 April 1921 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Woman Citizen, 27 January 1923 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Woman Citizen, 10 January 1925 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Woman Citizen, 21 March 1925 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Woman Citizen, 18 April 1925 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Woman Citizen, 2 May 1925 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Woman Citizen, 16 May 1925 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Woman Citizen, 13 June 1925 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Woman Citizen, 27 June 1925 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Woman Citizen, 11 July 1925 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Woman Citizen, 8 August 1925 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Woman Citizen, September 1925 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Woman Citizen clippings, 1919, 1922 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Woman Citizen index (handwritten, typed), 1917-1919 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - The Ave Maria (Notre Dame, Indiana), 23 September 1911 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - College Topics (University of Virginia), 27 April 1910 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - The Delineator, pp. 85-86, 151-152, February 1911 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - The Dixie Suffragist (Moravian Falls, Wilkes County, North Carolina), January 1915 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Fort Valley Message (Fort Valley, Georgia), January 1935 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Virginia Law Register, September 1919 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Shall Women Vote? A Book for Men by Conway Whittle Sams, 1913 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Pamphlets--The Electoral College and Presidential Suffrage, reprint from the Pennsylvania Law Review, and Votes for Women--Why and Why Not, from the Wilmington Dispatch, by Chief Justice Walter Clark of North Carolina, June 1917 and 22 February 1919 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets--The Bible on Women Voting; Guardianship of Children, reprint from Chicago Legal News; Illinois Laws Concerning Women; and Mayors of Five States or Votes for Women a Success,, by Catharine Waugh McCulloch,undated, 13 January 1912, undated, and February 1909 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets by author--Why Women Ought to Desire the Ballot by James Freeman Clarke; The Subjection of Women and the Enfranchisement of Women by Mrs. William H. Felton; Condorcet's Plea for the Citizenship of Women by John Morley; and Women, Economics, and the Ballot by Frances Squire Potter (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Reprints from North American Review--Woman Suffrage Throughout the World by Ida Husted Harper, and Woman and Democracy by Borden Parker Bowne, September 1907 and April 1910 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - World's Work extracts--Selma Lagerlof--Sweden's Idolized Writer by Velma Swanston Howard; Woman The Savior of the State by Selma Lagerlof and translated by Velma Howard; and The Present Plight of Labor by a World's Work staffer (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Pamphlets, no author--Woman Suffrage Facts Cartooned; Hare System of Proportional Representation; The World Court: Fifty Questions Answered; and Washington The Nation's Capital (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Leaflets--subject: Women Suffrage (10 leaflets) (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Leaflets--Right of Way, Virginia Railway and Power Company and White Slave Traffic, 15 March 1917 and undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Suffrage plays--How the Vote Was Won; Scenes from Political Life; The Soul of the World; and The Women of Achievement (program listing only) (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous articles on suffrage (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Hygiene and Morality by Lavinia L. Dock (jacket cover only) (Box 27, Folder 11)
- Series VII: Ephemera., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 29-30)
  Ephemera includes printing plate, slides advertising talks, ribbons, pins, and stamps from the Equal Suffrage League of Virginia.